Hi this is Sean Hobson.
One thing that you have to understand about the game of rebounding especially if you're playing a zone if who to box out on the zone.
Now obviously if you're in a man to man situation, you're on the guy that you're guarding.
You know who you're guarding, you know how they shoot, you know how they box out so it's much much easier.
But when your team plays a lot of zone like we do, you've got to learn how to box out and the most important thing is you have to understand the players that are in your area.
So, as Zach right here is playing the top of our zone he has to realize who is out here.
He has to know not only where the offensive guys are and the positions that they are on the floor, he also has to know where his fellow defenders are.
He knows if there's somebody else that is up here then they have to communicate and when the shot goes up, Zach will say I've got the wing you get the top and then I would box out here and Zach would box out there.
One thing you cannot do in the zone which we see a lot is when the shot goes up, if Zach just turns around to get the rebound, you're going to have this man from the top blitzing in and you're going to have the man from the wing coming in to rebound.
So you have to understand who's in your area and who's going to box out who.
You find the opposite colored jersey and you put a body on it.
It's very very important not only man to man but especially in the zone to box somebody out.